<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Daniel Cardoza</title>
    <link>http://danielcardoza.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Daniel Cardoza</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Daniel Cardoza</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 08:14:51 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://danielcardoza.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenophone : SMS forwarder using Twilio</title>
      <link>http://danielcardoza.com/blog/jenophone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielcardoza.com/blog/jenophone/</guid>
      <description>Overview When I moved to California after graduation, it became difficult to easily communicate with my girlfriend in Canada because of telecom issues.
The crux of the problem was the following:
 My phone plan has unlimited data and unlimited texting to US, Canada phone numnbers. My girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s phone plan had limited data (thank you Canadian telecoms) and only had unlimited texting in Canada.  I wanted to make communication easier between us, so I decided to make my own SMS forwarding service using Twilio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerca : Search a website&#39;s links</title>
      <link>http://danielcardoza.com/blog/cerca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielcardoza.com/blog/cerca/</guid>
      <description>Overview I recently had a problem where I wanted to verify that a website:
 did not link to a given website on a blacklist did not return non 2XX status codes for a given route  Although there are many utilities you can probably piece together to solve this problem, I decided to make my own utility Cerca (which is Catalan for search).
Problem Given a website URL, search the website for all external and internal links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://danielcardoza.com/blog/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://danielcardoza.com/blog/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to my blog!
This site was created and powered by the following:
 Hugo for static site generation Manis for the website theme Github Pages for hosting  Through this blog, I hope to write interesting posts about projects I am working on, self development and life in general.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>